[Music]
Hello friends, how are you all? We
hope you are well. In today's
video, we are going to tell you that
digital insurance has started through the CSC portal.
How will you do that insurance?
For this, today we will make a complete video and
show you. For this, first of all, we have to
open any browser on our computer.
After opening the browser, we will
open our CSC portal official website. As soon as the
website opens, we have to
click on the login option in the top corner. Just like
we login to our portal, you all
know that you have to login to your portal in the same way. When
we click on the login option,
we will be asked for our CSC ID
and password. Here you have to enter your
CSC ID and password.
After this, fill in the captcha code below
and then click on the sign in option.
As soon as we click on the sign in option, it will take
some time and
after this, our portal will be logged. Once
our portal is logged,
see, our portal has been logged. Here,
we have to search for the insurance option on the top menu bar
and type it above it.
As soon as we type, we will
get a list here.  In that, we have to
choose the Mota Society option below
because we are going to do third party insurance.
If you want to do first party, then
you can do Motor Comprehensive.
After this, we have to go to the search option and
search for digital or go digital. After this, we have to
choose one of the two options.
After this, on the next page, we have got the digital logo.
Here we have to
click on shinyness digital service connect. As soon as
we click there, the
portal opens in front of us. Here, health
insurance and bike insurance are not activated yet.
Here, only bike
insurance is activated. So, after clicking on the third wala
insurance, on the next page, it is being
asked for the registration number. So,
we have to enter the registration number of our vehicle.
As soon as we enter the registration number of the vehicle, then we will again be asked for two options.
First, if your policy is
expired, then you will
choose the first option. If your policy is
Paytm wala, then you will click there, then the
next page will open. Here all the details of your vehicle will be shown
like
registration number, model number,
variant of the bike and registration year. You have to
match everything with your RC book.
After this, if there is any correction,  We will
edit it by clicking on the edit option and then
we will click on the next option.
As soon as we click on the next option,
all our details will be verified here
and after verification, we will
see the premium on the next page. Here our first
option is for the first party
and the second third party cover is
for third party insurance, so if we do third party
insurance, then we have to
click on the third party cover option
and after this we have to come down,
as if we come down, then see here there are two
options, the first option is of 6000 and the second
is of 100000, so in this, if someone's property is damaged by our car, then the
other person will get up to one lakh, so
we will click on one lakh, as if I will
click on one lakh, then see the premium here, which has been
updated, which is ₹14 net
premium. After this, if we want to take
personal accident cover for the customer, which is of 15
lakhs, it is accidental cover, then you
will tick mark the first option and if you want to take passenger cover,
then click on the second option.  You have to click and
write in whatever cover is there,
you can do it, after this you have to
click on the next option, as soon as you
click on the next option, then
on the next option, you have to fill the personal details of the customer
like the name of a customer,
his pin code, his mobile number and his
email ID, so here in the first
option, their name will be filled automatically, the pin
code will also be filled up automatically, if
not then you can fill it, after this
you have to send an email, after filling the email, you have to
fill up the mobile number here,
after filling up the mobile number, we will
come down a little, then here we will be
asked for nominee details, here for free 843
which after adding GST has become 843 final premium,
after this we will tick mark here,
then
a copy of its policy will reach our WhatsApp, after this we have to
fill the address, you have to see the address in your RC book,
as the address is written in it,
you have to write the complete address here,
so let us quickly
write our address here, after writing the address,
we have nominee details below  In the nominee
details, we have to enter the
name of any member of our family or the family of our customer.
After entering the name, we have to enter the
relation here.
If the relation is brother, then it should be from the bridal party.
After this, we have to click on the continue option.
If we click on the continue option, then
our vehicle number,
engine number and change number will be automatically entered.
After this, we have the option below. If your
vehicle is on loan, then you have to tick mark here.
If it is not there, then do nothing.
After this, we have to click on the continue option. If
we click on the continue option, then
next we have to
fill in the details of our insurance here.
If you have those details, then you can
fill up those details here. After this,
if you want this cover, then you
can tick mark here. Our
final premium here is 843, which has been
told here after adding GST. Here,
we have to check all our previous insurances
on our old insurance and enter
its details here.  We have to fill it up here,
so let's go here and
fill it up by looking at our details from the old insurance.
After filling the details, we are being asked to
confirm once again that if we
want personal accident cover here, then we
can tick mark it. After this,
we have to click on the option of wearing it.
As if we are clicking on the option of wearing it, then
our application number has been
generated here. The premium that has
come here is 842 and 52 paise. After this,
we have to click on the option of proceed to payment.
As if we
will click on the option of proceed to payment, then it will
redirect us to the wallet page of CSC.
Here our amount is 842 rupees 52 paise
and the payment that will be deducted from our wallet is
747 and 88 paise. After this, if you want to
proceed further with the insurance, then here
we have to enter our password of CSC ID here
and after entering the password,
we have to click on the validate option.
As if we will click on the validate option, then on the
next page, we will be asked to enter our CSC ID.  You will be
asked for a valid password, if we
click on the valid password like a pin, our
policy will be generated and we
can print that policy and give it to the customer or
download it.
Heartfelt thanks to all of you for staying till the end of the video.
If you liked our video, please
like it and
share it with your friends so that they can also
get help. To get similar information,
if you are new to our channel, then
subscribe to our channel and turn on the bell icon
so that you keep getting this informative video from
time to time. Thank you
friends
[Music] [
Music]